Farzaneh Falakrou

Experience Designer

CONTACTS

- +393347520144
- Berlin, Germany
- @ farzaneh.falakrou@gmail.com
- in farzaneh-falakrou
- https://farzaneh-falakrou.github.io

SKILLS



TOOLS

Figma Miro Photoshop InDesign Illustrator HTML5 +CSS

EDUCATION

UI Specialisation Course | CareerFoundry **■** Sep 2023- Nov 2023

MSc in Urban Planning & Policy Design | Politecnico di Milano

BSc in Architecture | Azad University

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent Italian: Intermediate Persian: Mother tongue Germany: Elementary

CERTIFICATES

UX/UI Design Spec. | Coursera

Project Management Spec. | Coursera

SUMMARY

Associate Experience Designer with over 5 years of experience in architecture and urban planning, offering a unique blend of creativity and analytical thinking to create user-centric solutions. Demonstrated ability to translate complex design challenges into practical solutions through my involvement in projects of varying scales.

PROJECTS

UI Designer | Real Estate Responsive Web App

• Designed high-fidelity prototypes, showcasing visual elements including color, typography, icons that align with the project goal. Incorporated a style guide to ensure design consistency & scalability. Link to project

UX/UI Designer | Beauty Expert App

- Defined user needs and goals through user interviews and surveys, and developed personas, customer journey maps and sitemaps.
- Designed from low to high-fidelity screens, multiple prototype iterations and a style guide, refined through usability and preference tests.
- Developed and tested an AI-powered try on feature, achieving an average user satisfaction score of 6 out of 7. <u>Link to project</u>

UX Designer | Language Learning App

- Conducted user research including competitive analysis, user interviews, and surveys to gather data and develop personas and user flows.
- Created the Lo-Fi wireframes and prototypes, conducted usability tests.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Architect

Jun 2020 - Oct 2021

- Minimized design alterations by selecting precise materials, streamlining construction, and reducing costs.
- Exceeded client expectations by timely completing three interior projects through clear project plan, user feedback, and project management.
- Optimized limited residential space, meeting client preferences with 3D modeling for detailed layouts, resulting in a 15% increase in usable space through strategic furniture placement.

Urban Planning Intern | Labsimurb

Apr 2019 - Dec 2019

- Milan, Italy
- Implemented a 100 km sustainable bike path in south Milan, promoting eco-friendly mobility and addressing accessibility issues.
- Analysed environmental, social, and infrastructural vulnerabilities in Milan, informing strategic urban planning decisions that led to the implementation of sustainable solutions for a safer urban environment.
- Incorporated co-creation into urban planning by engaging stakeholders through digital platforms, resulting in more community-driven plans that addressed unique needs and enhanced overall livability.

Architect | Jahannama Architects

Jan 2015 – Jul 2017

- Isfahan, Iran
- Contributed in the entire design process of residential projects, creating detailed drawings and specifications within a cross-functional team.
- Confronted with diverse client preferences for a luxury residential project, detailed mood boards were developed, resulting in a 20% reduction in design revision cycles and achieving swift client approval.